[Glory]
[Episode 13]
My Lord.
It's gone wrong.
You chose the daily route
Miss Rong takes
because you wanted to
get close to Rong Shanbao.
Everything happened
just as you predicted,
My Lord.
After your accident,
no one dared to investigate
the Wei family case anymore.
I offered a pair of precious pearls
as a gift
and revealed several of
your mistakes as my pledge of loyalty.
Xu Song accepted my surrender
and entrusted me with important tasks,
promoting me all the way up.
You successfully infiltrated
the Rong family
and won Miss Rong's favor.
Cracking the Wei family case
is within sight.
His Majesty will surely
reward you generously.
Nothing seems bad at the time.
If I hadn't hit that sharp rock
and injured my brain,
the situation wouldn't have become
so complicated.
I'm no deity
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
who can foresee everything under heaven.
It's all because I was too arrogant,
so heaven played a trick on me.
I wove my own net
only to trap myself in it.
My Lord, are you worried about
Yang Dingchen's case?
Please rest assured, My Lord.
Once we find the owner of
those embroidered shoes,
the case will be solved.
Yunshu.
You know I've
always cared for you the most.
It's all Mr. He's fault
for flattering me so much.
I couldn't resist for a moment.
It's my fault.
I'll find you a better match
in the future.
Please don't blame me.
How would I dare?
Mr. He comes from a noble family.
How could I be worthy of him?
Xiangling, I have a headache.
I have some medicine for headaches.
It's perfect for your symptoms.
Guaranteed to cure you.
Come with me.
Yunyin.
What are you thinking about so intently?
I think I've seen the mark
on the shoe soles
somewhere before.
[Hualin Courtyard]
Shanbao!
Shanbao, help me!
Shanbao.
Shanbao!
Miss Rong.
All your account books and belongings
have been moved to Hualin Courtyard.
Miss Rong.
Lady Yunwan made a scene
for half the night,
crying for Mrs. Liang.
The entire back courtyard
was turned upside down.
She only settled down late at night.
When I just closed my eyes,
Lady Yunwan disappeared.
Mrs. Qiu.
Have two people watch over Yunwan
without leaving her side for a moment.
Don't let strangers frighten her.
Yes.
Miss Rong! Miss Rong!
How can this be my fault?
Lady Yunwan is so unstable,
who could possibly keep watch over her?
Miss Rong, please don't worry.
I've burned those shoes,
so they won't be found.
Do you think Lady Yunwan
might have seen something?
Wanwan was about to find Mrs. Liang.
She must have stumbled upon
Yang Dingchen's death
and got frightened.
Fortunately,
you weren't in the room that night.
Otherwise,
the Yang family would have implicated you.
How can you be sure the murderer
only wanted to kill Yang Dingchen?
What if he specifically chose
our wedding night
to kill me as well?
Miss Rong.
[Madam Yang]
Is Wanwan throwing another tantrum
because she can't see me?
[Mrs. Liang]
Did she sleep well at night?
I'm afraid no one
can watch over her properly.
When can I go out?
I just want to take a quick look.
I miss her.
I'll be careful.
I won't let them see me again.
Godmother,
people from your family is here.
It's your brother this time.
Do you want to see him?
No, no, no!
No, no!
No!
I won't go out.
Miss Rong.
I'll never dare again!
Please don't let me go out.
I won't go out.
Godmother, please get up.
You can't hide forever,
without seeing daylight again.
Let me wash your feet.
You ungrateful, disobedient thing!
Are you trying to scald me to death?
Mother.
Why have you upset
Mother again?
She's disrespectful and contradicts me.
You are my son,
so you must teach her a good lesson.
Mother.
Go on, go!
Quickly, go!
Not long after I married into the family,
I accidentally discovered my mother-in-law
having an affair.
She forced me to sleep with her lover,
and when I refused,
she incited Wei Kejian to beat me.
I passed out several times.
Each time, he would revive me,
begging me to understand
he couldn't disobey his mother.
After all these years,
whenever I close my eyes,
I can still smell
the badger oil used to treat my wounds.
Yes, he was a kind-hearted man.
He was forced into it.
But did I deserve to die?
What did I do wrong?
You did nothing wrong.
I had begged Father
and my brothers.
I pleaded with them to save me.
But they just said
it was my bad fate,
and I could change my husband
and his mom's attitude towards me.
As long as I'm willing to endure
and obey everything,
even hearts of stone
can be moved.
They would treat me well eventually.
But I can't bear it. I can't bear it.
Only the Rong family,
and your mother,
who was my dearest friend,
my only hope.
Only she would help me,
but now she's dead too.
She's dead.
You're my only hope now.
Please save me.
Save me, please save me.
Miss Rong!
Steward Lu was taken away by Lord Lang.
Greetings, Miss Rong.
Did that Lord Lang
give you any trouble?
No.
Then what did he say to you?
You've successfully
infiltrated the Rong family
and gained Miss Rong's favor.
The Wei family's case will be solved soon.
As for what you did before
or where you came from,
I don't care.
As long as you never deceive,
cheat,
or hide things from me,
that's enough.
He asked
who Mr. Yang had conflicts with
and who in Xinfang Pavilion
might be suspects.
I just told him the truth.
He didn't ask about anything else?
He also asked about
my background and origins,
but I managed to evade the questions.
I wonder if they found
the owner of those shoes.
Adult women's shoes
with phoenix or flower designs
on the sole are common,
but those carved with
the Five Poisons are rare.
They're more like what's used
during the Dragon Boat Festival
to ward off evil.
There are no children with seven-cun feet
in my family.
Wait a sec.
You may go now.
They don't seem to be searching for shoes
or matching footprints,
but looking for someone.
With a clear conscience,
why fear any questioning?
Keep an eye on these people.
You mean, Lord Lang?
And Lu Fusheng.
The courtyard is in chaos,
yet Miss Rong is still
concerned about the accounts.
When you went out earlier,
did you notice how others looked at you?
They were jealous!
Mr. Lu, I heard them saying
the Yang family
is making a big deal
about Mr. Yang's situation
because they want to marry Yitang
into the Rong family.
Who's been gossiping again?
Yang Dingchen died suddenly.
If someone else
marries into the Rong family,
the connection between two families
will weaken.
How could the Yang family accept that?
All that scheming for nothing.
Mr. Lu, wait for me!
Mr. Lu!
Haven't seen you for a while.
You've clearly become wealthy.
Tell me.
When are you going to pay
the debt you owe us?
Who are you people?
When did I ever owe you money?
A year ago at Jixiang Casino.
You pawned your house and land.
Then borrowed more from us brothers.
With principal and interest,
it's at least 500 taels by now.
You dare refuse to pay?
What scoundrels are you?
Where's the debt note
with his fingerprint?
You're just trying to extort him.
The note?
Yes, I'll get it for you.
I'll get it.
-Take him away.
-Jundai.
Move! We'll talk at the County Office.
Mr. Lu!
Come here.
Gentlemen, you didn't explain clearly
before dragging me here.
That's quite rude.
Lord Lu, don't blame us
for being ruthless.
You should have died earlier.
Since you're so hard to kill,
you'll just have to suffer more cuts.
Someone's coming! Run!
Mr. Lu! Mr. Lu!
Don't run!
I failed to protect you properly,
letting you suffer greatly.
I deserve to die.
Why are you all here?
Miss Rong said
the mansion has been unsettled lately.
She feared that you
might get into trouble going out alone.
She ordered us to protect you secretly.
Thankfully they came quickly,
otherwise I wouldn't have the face
to see Miss Rong again.
I was terrified.
It's fine. Let's go.
Mr. Lu, let me help you.
Mr. Lu, you're injured.
Let's go.
[Rong Mansion]
Let me do it.
Miss Rong.
It's my fault.
You got hurt because of me again.
How could this be your fault?
No, it is my fault.
I should have told you the truth earlier.
Your name is Lu Jianglai.
You're the Imperial Inspector
sent by the Emperor to Jiangnan.
You fell off a cliff
due to someone's scheme.
I was afraid
you might have ulterior motives,
so I was constantly on guard.
Only when I was certain
that you truly remembered nothing,
did I finally feel at ease.
The debt of saving my life is immense.
If it weren't for you,
there probably wouldn't be
a person named Lu Jianglai
in this world anymore.
Besides, I was still
recovering from my injuries then.
I would be defenseless
if you had pushed me
out the door.
It would have been easy
to kill me.
I don't want to waste
your two hundred-year-old ginseng roots.
That Lang Zhusheng
is probably a greedy man
who betrayed his master for personal gain.
For fame and fortune,
he sold you, his master,
to that scoundrel Xu Song.
The two of them conspired together
to make you
fall off a cliff and lose your memory,
and then hurriedly
reported your death to the capital
to confirm your demise.
Even if you leave the Rong family,
no one would dare recognize you
as Lu Jianglai.
Yesterday, Lang Zhusheng
saw you in the mansion.
He pretended not to know you,
but privately detained you
for questioning.
After confirming you truly don't remember
your past,
he simply set
his poisonous plan for today.
He planned to silence you permanently
to eliminate any future trouble.
This...
That isn't true, is it?
I had
the Jixiang Casino investigated,
but found no trace of those criminals.
Even at this point,
you still don't believe
he wants to harm you?
I feel dizzy.
Sometimes I remember things,
but other times it's all a blur.
If you hadn't sent people to protect me,
I would've...
He's very guilty-conscious.
From now on,
take more guards when you go out.
As long as
you remain part of the Rong family,
I don't believe he would dare harm you
openly.
Wait.
Are you just leaving like this?
Shanbao will inevitably suspect me.
Your life is what matters most.
Then come with me now
and leave the mansion together.
I can't leave.
The case of Wei family is still unsolved.
Look at my face.
That fiery lady
spat right in my face.
I've never seen
such a fierce woman in my life.
And she's merely
a cousin staying with the Rong family,
yet she's so arrogant.
It's clear that Miss Rong
will be even harder to deceive.
Do you really want to
pluck a tiger's whiskers？
All right, all right.
I have my own methods.
Miss Rong is usually cold as ice,
who knew she could care for someone?
Mr. Lu, it's a blessing in disguise.
This isn't right either.
Not this one.
Not this.
How long will this checking take?
Steward Cheng.
Officer.
You just need to check the size
in the ledger.
Why make such a fuss?
These people still have work to do.
We can't afford the delay.
My Lord said that
since girls and boys
around 15 or 16
grow so fast,
we need to look...
To look for a steed with its portrait.
Yes, for a steed.
The ledger is from last autumn.
Trying to match things now might not work.
Miss Rong.
They've gone too far.
They've even searched Hualin Courtyard.
Should we...?
Since Grandmother has given her orders,
let them do as they please.
I'll head back to the
tea plantation now.
The carriage is already prepared for you.
Xiu Qiong, you stay.
They took
shoemaking ledger
and went to
question Mrs. Cui from Zhegui Courtyard,
interrogating her thoroughly,
and insisting she was suspicious.
Miss Shen immediately lost her temper
and had them chased out
with a big broom.
Lord Lang personally pleaded with her
but was scolded terribly too.
They should know better
who we are.
Without any evidence,
they dare to barge in like this.
If they end up finding no evidence,
our Second Master in the capital
can have even the Prefect impeached.
Fortunately, the harvest
at the tea plantation
has finished before the Grain Rain.
If the tea production had been delayed,
Grandmother would have been truly furious.
Those people are making such a commotion.
I heard those women
in the courtyard gossiping
that those people kept staring at them
with strange looks.
If they're really looking for the culprit,
I don't think that's what they're after.
I just remembered!
Yunxi.
I knew I'd seen those shoes
somewhere before.
They belonged to Rong Yunwan!
They're Wanwan's.
I'll go tell Grandmother right away.
Not now.
Rong Yunwan was born simple-minded.
It's not strange that she wanders around.
Besides, you two
are at each other's throats all the time.
If you make a fuss about this,
and implicate the Rong family,
Grandmother will blame you for it.
We'd better wait a bit
and see how things develop.
Did you hear that?
Yes.
That night when I hosted the tea party,
you left early...
Lady Yunxi,
please don't get me in trouble.
Our He's tea shop
is located
just west of your Shanju Tea House.
The first batch of tea
has just been harvested over there.
As a young master,
how could I not make an appearance?
It's not like I am sold to your family.
Sit down.
You're holding such leverage
over Rong Shanbao.
Don't you want to make use of it?
The leverage I have
is far more than you think.
It's not time to use it yet.
So cautious, aren't you?
What if I told you
I could help you
bring that formidable Miss Rong down
from her pedestal?
I'm all ears.
Lady Yune painted a picture
and asked me to embroider
a fruit and vegetable wall hanging.
The peaches and plums
are easy to embroider,
but the eggplants and Buddha's hands
are really tricky for me.
I know your special embroidery stitch
is the finest here,
so I came to you first.
Miss Rong's favored maid,
Xiu Qiong,
is the one with the best needlework.
Why don't you ask her instead?
I don't like her.
I only like you.
Lady Yunxi, Lady Yune,
what brings you here?
Yunxi invited you here
because she has something for you to do.
I've always said Manzhu is talented.
She's determined to
take you into her service.
I don't deserve Lady Yunxi's praise.
Last December,
when you helped Miss Rong
with the New Year gifts,
you took quite a few “gifts”,
didn't you?
I wonder if Miss Rong knows about that?
Look at this girl.
She's terrified.
Don't worry,
I just need you to do a small favor.
I won't make things difficult for you.
Yeju,
I was just about to look for you.
At the back door,
that peddler has come again.
The pearl hairpin
and red silk handkerchief you want
have all been brought.
Everyone's picking through them now.
Xiang'er, I still have business here.
What business could be so urgent?
Let's go.
I...
Come on.
That damned Lang Zhusheng,
a pretentious scholar
out of nowhere,
made mountain out of a molehill,
causing such a commotion.
And Grandmother even tolerates him.
Xiangling, don't be upset.
Our Rong family has had a death case.
To quell public gossip,
and placate the Yangs,
we have to at least
make a show of cooperating.
Besides, Magistrate Lang
is only following orders.
Look how cautious he is being.
He's quite pitiful.
You are actually
speaking up for an outsider now.
Miss Shen,
the letter has been delivered to Mr. Bai.
That floral hairpin in your hair
looks pretty.
Come closer and let me see.
The pearl hairpin
was snatched by Yang'er.
I was flustered in the moment
and couldn't hold off so many of them.
So I only managed to grab this small one.
It's quite exquisitely made.
Who's Yang'er?
She's the needleworker
from Lady Yunxi's courtyard.
Three or four of them came,
surrounded me and wouldn't let go.
Tell me everything that happened today,
in exact detail.
Not a single word omitted.
Yes.
Yunshu.
Where are you going?
The last batch of first spring tea
has been picked.
All the fresh tea from every plantation
needs to be sent to Hualin Courtyard.
I'm going to check on it.
She went to the tea plantation.
I see.
What's going on with Yunxi's people now?
So many account books and letters.
How long will it take
to go through them all?
Your mistress
is rushed off her feet every day.
Look how late it is,
but she's still not back
from the tea plantation.
Just think about it.
Running such a large family business
is no easy task.
What's the big deal
about sharing a little of her burden?
Mr. Lu, you really care for her.
Look, isn't that Mr. Bai?
That servant leading the way
looks familiar.
Do you know him?
That's
He Si, who serves Mr. He.
He Xingming and Bai Yingsheng
are like fire and water.
How could they be together?
You didn't see wrong?
No mistake about it.
That He Si
loves gambling more than anything.
Whenever we servants
feel like a little gamble,
he's always around.
Go quickly and see
if He Xingming
is looking to cause trouble
for Bai Yingsheng.
Report back to me at once.
I'll be right back.
Mr. Lu.
This evening, Mr. He
ordered a table of fine food and wine.
He Xingming is hosting Bai Yingsheng?
Now that's something new.
Mr. Bai, come on,
have some more.
Bring another pot of wine!
Mr. He.
It's getting late.
I need study later,
so I really can't drink anymore.
If you don't drink my wine,
it means
you're still holding a grudge against me.
That's not it.
In this world,
there's no one more magnanimous
than you, Mr. He.
I'm flattered.
My verbal agreement with Lady Yunshu
doesn't make us truly married.
Since I can change my betrothal
to Lady Yunxi now,
why don't I allow you two
who have feelings for each other
form your own match?
Lady Yunxi kindly advised me today.
In the future, when you marry Lady Yunshu,
we'll become brothers-in-law!
Both under the Rong roof,
we're bound to help each other out.
Why be enemies?
Mr. He,
a true gentleman indeed.
But I really
have something to do later,
because I have an appointment
with Lady Yunshu.
Alright.
I won't delay your
important business.
Let's have three more drinks.
From now on,
let's put our grudges behind us
and renew our friendship.
Lady Yunwan, don't be upset anymore.
Look at what I have.
I don't want it.
I only want Mrs. Liang!
Lady Yunwan,
these are all specially
found for you by Miss Rong.
Let's stop making a fuss, shall we?
No more fussing.
Lady Yunwan, it's alright.
Mrs. Liang will come back.
Well...
isn't that nice?
How could you break
the teacups given by Lady Rong!
You were the one who broke them.
Enough, stop arguing.
What's happening outside?
Move aside.
When I was going to get bird's nest soup
for Lady Yunwan,
I saw two women
arguing in the kitchen.
I tried to reason with them,
but they started fighting instead.
Just look!
I was just trying to separate them,
and they even pulled my hair!
Go check quickly.
With that sharp tongue of yours,
you always pour oil on the fire.
Miss Rong will be back soon.
What will happen if she finds out?
You stay here
and take good care of Lady Yunwan.
It's scalding!
Go get a cooling fan.
A cooling fan?
Don't you know what a cooling fan is?
Mrs. Qiu put them away.
Go ask her for one.
Yes.
Lady Yunwan?
If you eat it up,
I'll take you to see Mrs. Liang.
How about that?
Really?
Mr. Bai?
Idiot.
Time to make our move.
Let's go.
Lady Yunwan,
Mrs. Liang is waiting for you there.
Didn't you two used to
play hide-and-seek here?
Hurry up now.
Mrs. Liang?
Lady Yunwan.
Who's there?
Who is it?
Stop!
Help! Someone help!
Go!
Lady Yunwan. Lady Yunwan.
Come and help quickly!
Help!
Save Lady Yunwan!
Lady Yunwan!
Hurry to Chongxi Hall
and inform Lady Rong!
Something terrible
has happened to Lady Yunwan!
Go now!
-Go!
-Yes.
Let's go!
Lady Yunwan!
Lady Rong!
Lady Yunwan is gone.
Mr. Bai!
Mr. Bai! Wake up!
Bai Yingsheng!
Bai Yingsheng! Wake up now!
Pull yourself together!
Wake up right now!
Mr. Lu! Mr. Lu!
Miss Rong is surrounded in the garden!
Lady Rong has been alerted.
You stay and watch him.
I'll go check the garden first.
Yes.
Grandmother!
Enough! This is no time for that.
Go quickly and see what's happening.
As soon as I got the news,
I was shocked to my core,
completely beside myself.
Only upon seeing you have I calmed down.
The garden is slippery.
Please watch your step.
The Rong family now
depends entirely on you.
Wanwan!
Miss Rong!
Lady Rong has arrived.
Grandmother, I just arrived home
when I heard
about Wanwan...
Lady Rong,
Mrs. Liang who served Lady Yunwan
fell ill and returned to her hometown.
Lady Yunwan missed her too much,
so she went to their
old play spot to look for her.
By the time we maids found her,
Lady Yunwan had fallen into
the large vat normally used
for collecting rainwater
and drowned.
The wicked live a thousand years.
How could she be dead?
Is she really dead?
I don't believe it.
I need to see for myself.
No matter how much you resent Wanwan,
she's already dead.
Can't you let her
rest in peace?
Quickly pull Lady Yunyin away!
Yunyin, Grandmother is grieving.
Please don't make a scene.
I know you sisters can't bear
to part with Yunwan,
but don't forget
the old rules of the Rong family.
Women shouldn't be involved in this.
Right.
I forgot in the confusion.
Wanwan's face looks terrible.
I wouldn't dare disturb you, Grandmother.
Better take her away.
Is everyone in Hualin Courtyard dead?
Grandmother entrusted Yunwan to you.
Why did you let her
run here alone?
Where were the people
supposed to be with her?
I know she was born
afflicted.
She'd caused so much annoyance to others.
Some have long wished for her death
to be rid of this burden.
It's my fault.
Had I known this would happen,
I should have kept Yunwan
in my own courtyard.
Day and night,
I would have watched over her myself.
I would never have let her
go alone, so desolate and wretched.
Grandmother, my poor Yunwan.
She was so young.
These people
have such cruel hearts.
You claim to care so much for Yunwan,
but in the past year,
you never visited her even once.
Yunwan's drowning
was something no one could have foreseen.
Shanbao was at the tea plantation.
She can't be in two places at once.
You can blame the servants for negligence,
so be it.
But is this insinuation,
necessary here?
You,
Xiangling.
Yun'e is just heartbroken about Yunwan.
She's flustered
and misspoke.
Shanbao will understand.
But tonight,
who was on duty?
How could such a lapse occur?
They must not go unpunished.
Lady Rong.
I was on watch tonight.
Everything is my fault.
I accept whatever punishment you deem fit.
You will be punished, of course.
Stand aside for now.
Where are tonight's patrollers?
Your Ladyship,
when the two of us
were patrolling near the east corner gate,
we glimpsed a figure in the darkness,
dressed like a scholar.
His silhouette looked very familiar.
He was hurrying away,
coming out from the side gate.
The more we called out,
the faster he fled.
We were about to chase after him
when we heard commotion in the garden
and couldn't pursue him further.
Did you get a clear look?
Who it was?
I recognized him.
It was Mr. Bai from Xinfang Pavilion.
Miss Rong.
Go bring him here.
Yes.
Fusheng.
Yunwan
was murdered.
Go.
Steward Cheng.
What has happened?
Nothing serious.
Lady Rong wishes to speak with Mr. Bai.
Everyone should return first.
Don't wander around tonight.
The Rong family is truly
going through difficult times.
One disaster follows another.
Mr. Yan.
Indeed.
Since ancient times,
fortune rarely comes in pairs,
but misfortune never travels alone.
Too much comfort always leads to calamity.
However, Miss Rong
is blessed with good fortune.
She'll certainly get through this safely.
Lady Rong, Mr. Bai's here.
Was it you who killed my granddaughter?
[Five Poisons and Fortune Pattern]
I wonder if the owner of those shoes
is found.
For adult women,
shoes with phoenix or flower designs
on the sole are common,
but those carved with
the Five Poisons are rare.
They're more like what's used
during the Dragon Boat Festival
to ward off evil.
In ancient times, people believed
the Fifth Lunar Month was a poisonous one,
when insects multiplied
and diseases spread easily.
To help children
safely get through summer,
people commonly had children wear
clothes embroidered with the Five Poisons:
gecko, scorpion, toad,
[Five Poison Pattern]
centipede and snake patterns,
symbolizing
fighting poison with poison for safety.
They also wore
five-colored thread bracelets.
These five colors
correspond to the Five Elements:
Wood, Fire, Earth, Metal, and Water.
Ancient people believed
they could balance yin and yang,
prevent illness and extend life,
becoming children's unique
Dragon Boat Festival accessories.
Besides the Dragon Boat Festival's
Five Poisons patterns,
there were also some
common decorative patterns
in ancient times,
such as the twining lotus,
[Eight Fortune Pattern]
symbolizing endless cycles of life,
representing good fortune.
The jade rabbit pattern represents
longevity and health.
[Jade Rabbit Pattern]
[Auspicious Cloud Pattern]
The auspicious cloud pattern
expresses ancient people's
aspiration for a better life.
These are all quite
characteristic patterns
of the Ming Dynasty.
Fairy, palace lantern,
squirrel, fruits,
and camellia patterns also possess
a kind of quaint charm.